

# **BRANDON BEST**

bbest.dev@gmail.com | (780) 977-9925 | brandonbest.ca/ 11441 Ellerslie Rd SW, Edmonton, AB T6W 1S9

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Blends academic training in accounting and finance with hands-on experience in management to provide proven organization, time management, and scheduling expertise. Experienced with managing schedules, directing teams, and overseeing projects through volunteer and leadership opportunities.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Alberta

September 2013 - August 2019

Bachelor of Science: Computing Science

Software Product Management, UofA (via Coursera)

October 2019 - December 2019

Bachelor of Science: Computing Science

### **QUALITIES**

- Collaborative team environment
- Entrepreneurial drive and work ethic
- Fast learner and enjoys expanding knowledge.
- Passion for technology
- Accountable and results driven

### **SKILLS**

- Java, Python, JavaScript, and Bootstrap
- React, Angular, Spring Framework, Google Firebase, and Node.js
- Android Mobile Development & Object Oriented Programming
- NoSQL (Firestore, Firebase Realtime Database) and SQL Databases (Oracle).
- UI/UX prototyping using Figma.
- Machine learning techniques and concepts.

### **WORK HISTORY**

System Analyst | Haemonetics Canada Ltd. - Edmonton, AB

05/2019 - PRESENT

- Software developer for our Donor Management System software which plasma donation clinics use to manage the operation.
- Semi-agile work environment.
- Product is a Java server project using tools like Spring Framework and Oracle SQL Database.
- Also helped develop a future SaaS product for donation center analytics which used tools like Angular, Postgres, and TypeORM.

Technical Systems Analyst | Royal Bank of Canada - Toronto, ON 08/2017 - 05/2019

 Worked on the frontend of an internal tool for portfolio managers. Frontend was done in Angular. Also worked on backend day one data loading processes to populate the application
database for launch. This was taking current information from internal spreadsheets
and loading it into the Oracle SQL database using Apache POI (Java).

Founder | Xpertz Software Corp. (more info on website)

05/2018 - 10/2019

- Enterprise SaaS platform for skill management and to analyze collaborative efforts within large organizations.
- Built a Slack Bot that allowed people to display skills in Slack and find others to
  collaborate with by searching based on skill. As well a peer-to-peer recognition
  system used to validate collaborative experiences and colleague's skills.
- Built Slack Bot using Firebase Functions (Google Cloud Functions) and Realtime Database (NoSQL) all in JavaScript.
- Also contracted a developer to help start building the MVP as a webapp using React.
- I started learning React during this process and have used it in subsequent projects.

#### **ACTIVITIES**

**VP Technology** | NeurAlbertaTech (more info on website)

02/2019 - 04/2019

- Lead the club in creating an idea for a project to submit to the NeuroTechX student club competition. We decided on a 2D shooter game controlled by alpha brain waves using a Muse.
- Help organize the team structure and work process as well contribute to programming some of the game visuals.

Graduate | N Y-Combinator Startup School 07/2019 - 09/2019

- 10 week program on how to build and scale successful technology startups.
- Run by YC which is the premier startup accelerator in the world.